

# Nguyen Vu Quyen

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ho Chi Minh - 0869225891 - leo.quyennguyen@gmail.com

# Career Objective

After years in software development industry, I have been experienced with PHP and Python, mainly building API services, websites. I enjoy learning new things in my free

My hobbies are reading, playing basketball, traveling, cycling and hangout with my friends.

# Experience

# Teko

**Finance Management System (FMS)** 

(11/2018)

Description:

FMS plays the role of recording vouchers and events of other systems that increase or decrease the liabilities of the subjects managed by FMS. Each voucher or events will generate debt accounting, and from debt accounting will generate summary reports to track the debt status of specific debtors or orders.

- Contributed in building system architect, following business logic.
- Monitored to track and fix any error occurs.
- Contributed solutions for download millions of records.

Tech skills:

Microservices, Python, Rabbitmq, Docker, k8s, Grafana, linux server

#### Grab

(06/2018 - 10/2018)

#### Partner gateway

Description:

Building a platform for 3rd-party developers to create their own applications and services that access data in grab.

- Evaluated pros and cons between API gateways such as Tyk, Kong... to find out which tool is most suitable for our needs.
- Used Docker to setup and demonstrate how each API gateway works.

Tech skills:

Microservices, Go, Docker, Kibaba, Grafana, Datadog

# Admicro – VCCorp

(09/2015 - 06/2018)

#### Adx, Admarket, PRContent

Description:

Web app for campaign, banner management, export reports.

- Optimized website performance by refactored code.
- Wrote store procedures in order to interact with database due to restricted security.

Tech skills:

PHP (Codelgniter), MySQL, Bootstrap, jQuery

#### OffShore: worked with Viettel

Description:

Web app for expanded program on immunization.

- Worked with MVC model.
- Writing query using lambda expression.

Tech skills:

.NET (Entity Framework), Oracle, Jquery

#### UrJapan

Description:

A website which helps Thai tourists come to visit Japan.

- Developed responsive website, optimized UI/UX.
- Implemented google and facebook APIs.

Tech skills:

PHP (CakePHP), MySQL, Bootstrap, Jquery

SmartOSC (04/2014 – 10/2014)

# Vaxiorder

Description:

A website which allows admin to manage the products, orders and bills. Logged in users can track their orders including products, prices and status. My duties is contributed in build a module for manage suppliers, products, login system.

Tech skills:

PHP 5.3, MySQL, Jquery, Bootstrap

#### Cava-bien

Description:

An e-commerce website for selling women's clothes, shoes and accessories based on Magento.

Tech skills:

PHP (Magento Enterprise 1.13), MySQL

#### Freelance

#### **Football Management System (FMS)**

Description:

Built booking field management eco-system for VECGROUP.

- Analyzed customer needs to write WBS.
- Designed database structure, project architecture follow repositories-service pattern, and implemented business logics with my partner.

Tech skills:

PHP 7.2 (Laravel 5.8), MySQL, JWT

#### **PysTravel**

Description:

Built booking system for travel agency.

- Analyzed customer needs to write WBS.
- Designed database structure, file structure follow repository pattern, and implemented business logics with my partner.

Tech skills:

PHP 5.6 (Laravel 4.2), Angular 1, MySQL

#### Manta.vn

Description:

An e-commerce system for selling functional foods.

- Design database.
- Applied repository pattern to project.

Helped deploy project to EC2.

Tech skills:

PHP 7.0 (Laravel 5.3), MySQL

# **Technical Skills**

### Languages

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery

Backend: PHP, Python, Go

#### **Databases**

• MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle, Redis

#### **Architectures**

- Microservices, Docker, OOP, RESTful services, gRPC, graphQL, git, SVN
- Design pattern: repositories-services, CQRS

## Education

# Hanoi University of Science and Technology

The degree of master of engineer – Software engineering (2016 – 2018)

## National University of Civil Engineer

The degree of engineer – Information Technology (2009 – 2014)

#### Languages

- Vietnamese Native speaker
- English Upper intermediate (B1, TOEIC 720)